veganricha.com 2018-12-23

# Privacy Policy - Vegan Richa

I (Richa) deeply care about you and your privacy. I am wary of your personal information, your interactions with me on and off the blog. Your privacy is really important to me and I always keep it in mind whenever the question of privacy and securing that information comes up. Below outlines what is received and logged when you visit [www.veganricha.com](https://www.veganricha.com/) and how it is used. Blog automatically uses https so that your data on the wire is secured. If you have any questions about the policy below, feel free to contact me at [richahingle@gmail.com](mailto:richahingle@gmail.com)

I will be updating this page from time to time with modified date at the bottom. You should check this page to ensure that you are up-to-date with the latest policy.

###  **Logs**

Our log files on our secure servers store all visitors to the site, their IP address and comments. None of this can identify you directly. You can choose to use your email and identify yourself in the comments which stays in our database as comment to the post.

Based on above logs we may collect the following information:

  * contact information including email address
  * location information
  * other information relevant to giveaway and offers

We use this information to improve the content of the blog as well as understand the pattern of visits and users on the site.

###  **Cookies**

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

###  **Comments**

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection. Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

###  **Media**

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

###  **Analytics**

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyze data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Cookies used by Google analytics in particular is really important for us to understand our visitors on the site. We use it to measure traffic at different times and places in the world. Here is more information from their Google.

From: <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245>

_Google Analytics mainly uses first-party cookies to report on user interactions on your website. These cookies are used to store non-personally identifiable information. Browsers do not share first-party cookies across domains._

 _For customers who use Google Analytics Advertising Features, Google advertising cookies are used to enable features, such as Remarketing, for products like AdWords on the Google Display Network. For more information about how Google uses advertising cookies, visit the[Google Advertising Privacy FAQ](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/technologies/ads/). To manage settings for these cookies and opt-out of these features, visit the [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/)._

###  **Advertising**

Our advertisers may also use similar means to track such visits. Privacy policy of the networks being used are below where you should be able to find more information.

<http://www.gourmetads.com/about/privacy-policy>

These Ad vendors may use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies to serve you advertisements tailored to interests you have shown by browsing on this and other sites you have visited, to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before and to avoid sending you duplicate advertisements. In doing so, these vendors may collect non-personal data such as your browser type, your operating system, Web pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed, and other clickstream data. The use of cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies by these advertising service vendors is subject to their own privacy policies.

You should go through the individual privacy policy and make sure you understand how you can disable cookies if required.

###  **Links to other websites**

Content on our site contain links to other websites such as other bloggers, affiliates such as Amazon or other media sites such as YouTube. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

### How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

###  **Controlling your personal information**

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:

  * whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes
  * If you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by contacting us.
  * If you want us to delete your email address from our servers, you may do so at any time by contacting us.
  * Understand how can you accept, reject of disable cookies on individual sites.
  * Delete existing cookies from your computer.

We do not sell, rent, trade, or otherwise share personal information we have unless we have prior consent or we are required by the law. 

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please contact us.

* * *

## Source: WP Recipe Maker

Bootstrapped Ventures, the developer of WP Recipe Maker, does not have access to any of the data collected by the plugin. This is all stored in your local database and not communicated back to us. Take note of the following topics for your own privacy policy.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When comment ratings are enabled we store the rating a user has given to a recipe along with the personal data WordPress core stores.

### Cookies

When user ratings are enabled we store a WPRM_User_Voted_%recipe% cookie (with %recipe% the ID of the recipe) that contains the rating this user has given to a particular recipe. This cookie is used as (one of the) measures to prevent rating spam.

### IP Address

When user ratings are enabled we store the IP address upon voting. This is used as (one of the) measures to prevent rating spam.

### Their own manually input information

With the Recipe Submission feature personal data can be collected, depending on the fields that were added to the form. This can include the user email and name. When using the reCAPTCHA feature you will be agreeing to their terms of use and privacy policy.

## How long we retain your data

Our cookies are stored for 30 days. User submitted data is stored indefinitely in the local database.

* * *

## Source: WP Ultimate Post Grid

WP Ultimate Post Grid does not collect any data. Fonts in the grid templates will be loaded from the Google Web Font API (fonts.googleapis.com) unless changed in the Template Editor. You will be agreeing to their Terms of Use and Privacy Policy.

* * *

 _Last updated on: 05/26/18_
